<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Researching ....</title>
<subtitle type="text">A short tagline</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2015-09-21T16:24:54+01:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Bruno Lima</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Approach for Automated Scenario-based Testing of Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/publications/ICSOFT" />
  <id>/publications/ICSOFT</id>
  <published>2015-07-22T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-07-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scitepress.org/DigitalLibrary/Link.aspx?doi=10.5220/0005558602410250&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruno Lima and João Pascoal Faria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The growing dependence of our society on increasingly complex software systems, makes software testing ever more important and challenging. In many domains, such as healthcare and transportation, several independent systems, forming a heterogeneous and distributed system of systems, are involved in the provisioning of end-to-end services to users. However, existing testing techniques, namely in the model-based testing field, provide little tool support for properly testing such systems. Hence, in this paper, we propose an approach and a toolset architecture for automating the testing of end-to-end services in distributed and heterogeneous systems. The tester interacts with a visual modeling frontend to describe key behavioral scenarios, invoke test generation and execution, and visualize test results and coverage information back in the model. The visual modeling notation is converted to a formal notation amenable for runtime interpretation in the backend. A distributed test monitoring and control infrastructure is responsible for interacting with the components of the system under test, as test driver, monitor and stub. At the core of the toolset, a test execution engine coordinates test execution and checks the conformance of the observed execution trace with the expectations derived from the visual model. A real world example from the Ambient Assisted Living domain is presented to illustrate the approach.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/publications/ICSOFT&quot;&gt;An Approach for Automated Scenario-based Testing of Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on July 22, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Testing and Certification Methodology for an Open Ambient-Assisted Living Ecosystem]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/publications/IJEHMC" />
  <id>/publications/IJEHMC</id>
  <published>2014-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.igi-global.com/article/a-testing-and-certification-methodology-for-an-open-ambient-assisted-living-ecosystem/124289&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;João Pascoal Faria and Bruno Lima and Tiago Boldt Sousa and Angelo Martins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cope with the needs raised by the demographic changes in our society, several Ambient-Assisted Living (AAL) technologies have emerged in recent years, but those ‘first offers’ are often monolithic, incompatible and thus expensive and potentially not sustainable. The AAL4ALL project aims at improving that situation through the development of an open ecosystem of interoperable AAL components (products and services), tied together by an integration infrastructure, comprising a message-queue based service bus and gateways bridging the communication with devices. To that end, the project encompasses the specification of interfaces and requirements for interoperable components, against which candidates can be tested and certified before entering the ecosystem. This paper proposes a testing and certification methodology for such an ecosystem. Besides fulfilling specified pre-requisites, candidate components must pass unit tests that check their conformance with interface specifications and integration tests that check their semantic interoperability with other components in specified orchestration scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/publications/IJEHMC&quot;&gt;A Testing and Certification Methodology for an Open Ambient-Assisted Living Ecosystem&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on December 31, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Testing and Certification Methodology for an Ambient-Assisted Living Ecosystem]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/publications/Healthcom2013" />
  <id>/publications/Healthcom2013</id>
  <published>2013-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpls/abs_all.jsp?arnumber=6720744&amp;amp;tag=1&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;João Pascoal Faria and Bruno Lima and Tiago Boldt Sousa and Angelo Martins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cope with the needs raised by the demographic changes in our society, several Ambient-Assisted Living (AAL) technologies have emerged in recent years, but those ‘first offers’ are often monolithic, incompatible and thus expensive and poten- tially not sustainable. The AAL4ALL project aims at improving that situation through the development of an open ecosystem of interoperable products and services for AAL, tied together via an integration infrastructure. To that end, the project encompasses the specification of a set of reference models and requirements for interoperable products and services, against which candidate products and services can be tested and certified, and subse- quently integrated as components of the ecosystem. This paper proposes a testing and certification methodology for such an ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/publications/Healthcom2013&quot;&gt;A Testing and Certification Methodology for an Ambient-Assisted Living Ecosystem&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on October 09, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>