<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Researching ....</title>
<subtitle type="text">A short tagline</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io" />
<updated>2018-07-24T17:02:11+01:00</updated>
<id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/</id>
<author>
  <name>Bruno Lima</name>
  <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/</uri>
  <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automatic Model Transformation from UML Sequence Diagrams to Coloured Petri Nets]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/MODESWARD2018" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/MODESWARD2018</id>
  <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.5220/0006731806680679&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;João Soares, Bruno Lima and João Pascoal Faria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UML Sequence Diagrams are used in different domains for specifying the required behaviour of software-based systems. However, the created diagrams are often used only as documentation, and not as a basis for generating subsequent lifecycle artifacts or for automated analysis. Several authors have proposed the transformation of Sequence Diagrams to executable Coloured Petri Nets (CPN), for simulation and testing purposes, but the transformations are not automated or are implemented in an ad-hoc way. To overcome those limitations, we present in this paper an approach to automatically translate Sequence Diagrams to CPN ready for execution with CPN Tools, taking advantage of model-to-model transformation techniques provided by the Eclipse Modelling Framework (EMF). The transformation rules are implemented in the Epsilon Transformation Language. We use the standard UML metamodel provided by EMF and the CPN metamodel provided by CPN Tools, so any Sequence Diagram created with an EMF compliant modelling tool can be transformed. An application example is presented to better illustrate the approach.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/MODESWARD2018&quot;&gt;Automatic Model Transformation from UML Sequence Diagrams to Coloured Petri Nets&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on January 23, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conformance Checking in Integration Testing of Time-constrained Distributed Systems based on UML Sequence Diagrams]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSOFT2017" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSOFT2017</id>
  <published>2017-07-24T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-07-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scitepress.org/DigitalLibrary/PublicationsDetail.aspx?ID=oJ9x95EPsTs=&amp;amp;t=1&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruno Lima and João Pascoal Faria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The provisioning of a growing number of services depends on the proper interoperation of multiple products, forming a new distributed system, often subject to timing requirements. To ensure the interoperability and timely behavior of this new distributed system, it is important to conduct integration tests that verify the interactions with the environment and between the system components. Integration test scenarios for that purpose may be conveniently specified by means of UML sequence diagrams (SDs) enriched with time constraints. The automation of such integration tests requires that test components are also distributed, with a local tester deployed close to each system component, coordinated by a central tester. The distributed observation of execution events, combined with the impossibility to ensure clock synchronization in a distributed system, poses special challenges for checking the conformance of the observed execution traces against the specification, possibly yielding inconclusive verdicts. Hence, in this paper we investigate decision procedures and criteria to check the conformance of observed execution traces against a specification set by a UML SD enriched with time constraints. The procedures and criteria are specified in a formal language that allows executing and validating the specification. Examples are presented to illustrate the approach.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSOFT2017&quot;&gt;Conformance Checking in Integration Testing of Time-constrained Distributed Systems based on UML Sequence Diagrams&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on July 24, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Survey on Testing Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems: The State of the Practice]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/CCIS" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/CCIS</id>
  <published>2017-07-12T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-319-62569-0_5&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruno Lima and João Pascoal Faria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed and heterogeneous systems (DHS), running over interconnected mobile and cloud-based platforms, are used in a growing number of domains for provisioning end-to-end services to users. Testing DHS is particularly important and challenging, with little support being provided by current tools. In order to assess the current state of the practice regarding the testing of DHS and identify opportunities and priorities for research and innovation initiatives, we conducted an exploratory survey that was responded by 147 software testing professionals that attended industry-oriented software testing conferences. The survey allowed us to assess the relevance of DHS in software testing practice, the most important features to be tested in DHS, the current status of test automation and tool sourcing for testing DHS, and the most desired features in test automation solutions for DHS. Some follow up interviews allowed us to further investigate drivers and barriers for DHS test automation. We expect that the results presented in the paper are of interest to researchers, tool vendors and service providers in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/CCIS&quot;&gt;A Survey on Testing Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems: The State of the Practice&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on July 12, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Towards Decentralized Conformance Checking in Model-Based Testing of Distributed Systems]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSTW2017" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSTW2017</id>
  <published>2017-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2017-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7899081/&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruno Lima and João Pascoal Faria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a growing number of domains, the provisioning of end-to-end services to the users depends on the proper interoperation of multiple products, forming a new distributed system. To ensure interoperability and the integrity of this new distributed system, it is important to conduct integration tests that verify not only the interactions with the environment but also the interactions between the system components. Integration test scenarios for that purpose may be conveniently specified by means of UML sequence diagrams, possibly allowing multiple execution paths. The automation of such integration tests requires that test components are also distributed, with a local tester deployed close to each system component, and a central tester coordinating the local testers. In such a test architecture, it is important to minimize the communication overhead during test execution. Hence, in this paper we investigate conditions upon which conformance errors can be detected locally (local observability) and test inputs can be decided locally (local controllability) by the local testers, without the need for exchanging coordination messages between the test components during test execution. The conditions are specified in a formal specification language that allows executing and validating the specification. Examples of test scenarios are also presented, illustrating local observability and controllability problems associated with optional messages without corresponding acknowledgment messages, races and non-local choices.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSTW2017&quot;&gt;Towards Decentralized Conformance Checking in Model-Based Testing of Distributed Systems&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on March 17, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[MT4A: a no-programming test automation framework for Android applications]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/A-TEST2016" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/A-TEST2016</id>
  <published>2016-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2994300&amp;amp;CFID=862843089&amp;amp;CFTOKEN=51893474&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiago Coelho, Bruno Lima and João Pascoal Faria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The growing dependency of our society on increasingly complex software systems, combining mobile and cloud-based applications and services, makes the test activities even more important and challenging. However, sometimes software tests are not properly performed due to tight deadlines, due to the time and skills required to develop and execute the tests or because the developers are too optimistic about possible faults in their own code. Although there are several frameworks for mobile test automation, they usually require programming skills or complex configuration steps. Hence, in this paper, we propose a framework that allows creating and executing tests for Android applications without requiring programming skills. It is possible to create automated tests based on a set of pre-defined actions and it is also possible to inject data into device sensors. An experiment with programmers and non-programmers showed that both can develop and execute tests with a similar time. A real world example using a fall detection application is presented to illustrate the approach.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/A-TEST2016&quot;&gt;MT4A: a no-programming test automation framework for Android applications&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on November 18, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Towards the Online Testing of Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems with Extended Petri Nets]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/QUATIC2016" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/QUATIC2016</id>
  <published>2016-09-09T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-09-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/7814554/&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruno Lima and João Pascoal Faria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The growing dependence of our society on increasingly complex software systems makes software testing ever more important and challenging. In many domains, such as healthcare and transportation, several independent systems, forming a heterogeneous and distributed system of systems, are involved in the provisioning of end-to-end services to users. However, existing testing techniques, namely in the model-based testing field, provide little support for properly testing such systems. To bridge the gaps identified in the state of the art we intend to develop a research work where the main goal is to significantly reduce the cost of testing distributed and heterogeneous systems, from the standpoint of time, resources and expertise required, as compared to existing approaches. For that, we propose a preliminary approach and a toolset architecture for automating the testing of end-to-end services in distributed and heterogeneous systems. The tester interacts with a visual modeling frontend to describe key behavioral scenarios, invoke test generation and execution, and visualize test results and coverage information back in the model. The visual modeling notation is converted to a formal notation amenable for runtime interpretation in the backend. A distributed test monitoring and control infrastructure is responsible for interacting with the components of the system under test, as test driver, monitor and stub. At the core of the toolset, a test execution engine coordinates test execution and checks the conformance of the observed execution trace with the expectations derived from the visual model. A real world example from the Ambient Assisted Living domain is presented to illustrate the approach. As future work we intend to develop distributed and incremental algorithms for online testing of distributed and heterogeneous systems based on Extended Petri Nets at runtime and validate them in real world case studies.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/QUATIC2016&quot;&gt;Towards the Online Testing of Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems with Extended Petri Nets&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on September 09, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems: State of the Practice]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSOFT2016" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSOFT2016</id>
  <published>2016-07-24T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-07-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scitepress.org/DigitalLibrary/PublicationsDetail.aspx?ID=uf6rOesekZg=&amp;amp;t=1&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruno Lima and João Pascoal Faria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a growing number of domains, such as health-care and transportation, several independent systems, forming a heterogeneous and distributed system of systems, are involved in the provisioning of end-to-end services to users. Testing such systems, running over interconnected mobile and cloud-based platforms, is particularly important and challenging, with little support being provided by current tools. In order to assess the current state of the practice regarding the testing of distributed and heterogeneous systems (DHS) and identify opportunities and priorities for research and innovation initiatives, we conducted an exploratory survey that was responded by 147 software testing professionals that attended industry-oriented software testing conferences, and present the main results in this paper. The survey allowed us to assess the relevance of DHS in software testing practice, the most important features to be tested in DHS, the current status of test automation and tool sourcing fo r testing DHS, and the most desired features in test automation solutions for DHS. We expect that the results presented in the paper are of interest to researchers, tool vendors and service providers in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSOFT2016&quot;&gt;Testing Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems: State of the Practice&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on July 24, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automated Scenario-based Testing of Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICST2016" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICST2016</id>
  <published>2016-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?arnumber=7515492&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruno Lima&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this document we outline a Ph.D. research plan and a summary of preliminary results on test automation for distributed and heterogeneous systems.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICST2016&quot;&gt;Automated Scenario-based Testing of Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on April 15, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Model-Based Approach for Product Testing and Certification in Digital Ecosystems]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSTW2016" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSTW2016</id>
  <published>2016-04-11T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2016-04-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?arnumber=7528963&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruno Lima and João Pascoal Faria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a growing number of domains, such as ambient- assisted living (AAL) and e-health, the provisioning of end-to-end services to the users depends on the proper interoperation of multiple products from different vendors, forming a digital ecosystem. To ensure interoperability and the integrity of the ecosystem, it is important that candidate products are independently tested and certified against applicable interoperability requirements. Based on the experience acquired in the AAL4ALL project, we propose in this paper a model-based approach to systematize, automate and increase the assurance of such testing and certification activities. The approach encompasses the construction of several models: a feature model, an interface model, a product model, and unit and integration test models. The abstract syntax and consistency rules of these models are specified by means of metamodels written in UML and Alloy and automatically checked with Alloy Analyzer. Using the model finding capabilities of Alloy Analyzer, integration tests can be automatically generated from the remaining models, through the composition and instantiation of unit tests. Examples of concrete models from the AAL4ALL project are also presented.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSTW2016&quot;&gt;A Model-Based Approach for Product Testing and Certification in Digital Ecosystems&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on April 11, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automated Testing of Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems Based on UML Sequence Diagrams]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/CCIS" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/CCIS</id>
  <published>2016-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-319-30142-6_21&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruno Lima and João Pascoal Faria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The growing dependence of our society on increasingly complex software systems makes software testing ever more important and challenging. In many domains, several independent systems, forming a distributed and heterogeneous system of systems, are involved in the provisioning of end-to-end services to users. However, existing test automation techniques provide little tool support for properly testing such systems. Hence, we propose an approach and toolset architecture for automating the testing of end-to-end services in distributed and heterogeneous systems, comprising a visual modeling environment, a test execution engine, and a distributed test monitoring and control infrastructure. The only manual activity required is the description of the participants and behavior of the services under test with UML sequence diagrams, which are translated to extended Petri nets for efficient test input generation and test output checking at runtime. A real world example from the Ambient Assisted Living domain illustrates the approach.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/CCIS&quot;&gt;Automated Testing of Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems Based on UML Sequence Diagrams&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on February 25, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Approach for Automated Scenario-based Testing of Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSOFT" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSOFT</id>
  <published>2015-07-22T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-07-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scitepress.org/DigitalLibrary/Link.aspx?doi=10.5220/0005558602410250&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruno Lima and João Pascoal Faria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The growing dependence of our society on increasingly complex software systems, makes software testing ever more important and challenging. In many domains, such as healthcare and transportation, several independent systems, forming a heterogeneous and distributed system of systems, are involved in the provisioning of end-to-end services to users. However, existing testing techniques, namely in the model-based testing field, provide little tool support for properly testing such systems. Hence, in this paper, we propose an approach and a toolset architecture for automating the testing of end-to-end services in distributed and heterogeneous systems. The tester interacts with a visual modeling frontend to describe key behavioral scenarios, invoke test generation and execution, and visualize test results and coverage information back in the model. The visual modeling notation is converted to a formal notation amenable for runtime interpretation in the backend. A distributed test monitoring and control infrastructure is responsible for interacting with the components of the system under test, as test driver, monitor and stub. At the core of the toolset, a test execution engine coordinates test execution and checks the conformance of the observed execution trace with the expectations derived from the visual model. A real world example from the Ambient Assisted Living domain is presented to illustrate the approach.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/ICSOFT&quot;&gt;An Approach for Automated Scenario-based Testing of Distributed and Heterogeneous Systems&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on July 22, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Testing and Certification Methodology for an Open Ambient-Assisted Living Ecosystem]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/IJEHMC" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/IJEHMC</id>
  <published>2014-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.igi-global.com/article/a-testing-and-certification-methodology-for-an-open-ambient-assisted-living-ecosystem/124289&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;João Pascoal Faria and Bruno Lima and Tiago Boldt Sousa and Angelo Martins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cope with the needs raised by the demographic changes in our society, several Ambient-Assisted Living (AAL) technologies have emerged in recent years, but those ‘first offers’ are often monolithic, incompatible and thus expensive and potentially not sustainable. The AAL4ALL project aims at improving that situation through the development of an open ecosystem of interoperable AAL components (products and services), tied together by an integration infrastructure, comprising a message-queue based service bus and gateways bridging the communication with devices. To that end, the project encompasses the specification of interfaces and requirements for interoperable components, against which candidates can be tested and certified before entering the ecosystem. This paper proposes a testing and certification methodology for such an ecosystem. Besides fulfilling specified pre-requisites, candidate components must pass unit tests that check their conformance with interface specifications and integration tests that check their semantic interoperability with other components in specified orchestration scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/IJEHMC&quot;&gt;A Testing and Certification Methodology for an Open Ambient-Assisted Living Ecosystem&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on December 31, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Testing and Certification Methodology for an Ambient-Assisted Living Ecosystem]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/Healthcom2013" />
  <id>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/Healthcom2013</id>
  <published>2013-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2013-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Lima</name>
    <uri>http://Bruno-Lima.github.io</uri>
    <email>bruno.lima [at] fe.up.pt</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpls/abs_all.jsp?arnumber=6720744&amp;amp;tag=1&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;icon-pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; (link for download)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;João Pascoal Faria and Bruno Lima and Tiago Boldt Sousa and Angelo Martins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cope with the needs raised by the demographic changes in our society, several Ambient-Assisted Living (AAL) technologies have emerged in recent years, but those ‘first offers’ are often monolithic, incompatible and thus expensive and poten- tially not sustainable. The AAL4ALL project aims at improving that situation through the development of an open ecosystem of interoperable products and services for AAL, tied together via an integration infrastructure. To that end, the project encompasses the specification of a set of reference models and requirements for interoperable products and services, against which candidate products and services can be tested and certified, and subse- quently integrated as components of the ecosystem. This paper proposes a testing and certification methodology for such an ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io/publications/Healthcom2013&quot;&gt;A Testing and Certification Methodology for an Ambient-Assisted Living Ecosystem&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Bruno Lima at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Bruno-Lima.github.io&quot;&gt;Researching ....&lt;/a&gt; on October 09, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>